20 chapter 21 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is In the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 21 The Parting Now I had lived in this happy
place 3 years years, but sad changes were about to come over us. We heard from time
to time that our mistress was ill. The doctor was often at the house, and the
master looked grave and anxious. Then we heard that she must leave her home at
once, and go to a warm country for 2 or 3 years. The news fell upon the household
like the talling of a deathbell. Everybody was sorry; but the master began directly to make
arrangements for breaking up his establishment and leaving
England. We used to hear it talked about in our stable; indeed, nothing else was talked
about Jon went about his work silent and sad, and Joe scarcely whistled. There was
a great deal of coming and going; Ginger and I had full
work. The first of the party who went were Miss Jesse and Flora, with their
governs They came to bid us goodbye They hugged poor Mary legs like an old friend,
and so indeed he was. Then we heard what had been arranged
for us. Master had sold Ginger and me to his old friend, the L of for he thought
we should have a good place there Merry legs he had given to the Vicor who was
wanting a pony for Mrs Bloomfield but it was on the condition that he should
never be sold, and that when he was past work he should be shot and buried. Joe
was engaged to take care of him and to help in the house, so I thought that Mery
legs was well off Jon had the offer of several good places, but he said he
should wait a little and look round.
The evening before they left the master came into the stable to give some
directions, and to give his horses the last pat. He seemed very low-spirited; I
knew that by his voice. I believe we horses can tell more by the voice than many men
can. “Have you decided what to do, John?” he said. “I found you have not accepted
either of those offers.” “No, sir I've made up my mind that
if I could get a situation with some First Rate cult breaker and horse
trainer it would be the right thing for me. Many young animals are frightened and
spoiled by wrong treatment, which need not be if the right man took them in
hand. I always get on well with horses, and if I could help some of them to a
fair start I should feel as if I were doing some good. What do you think of it,
sir?” “I don't know a man anywhere,” said master, “that I should think so suitable
for it as yourself. You understand horses, and somehow they understand you, and in
time you might set up for yourself; I think you could not do better. If in any
way I can help you, write to me. I shall speak to my agent in London, and leave
your character with him.” Master gave John the name and address, and then he thanked him for his
long and faithful service; but that was too much for John. “Pray, don't, sir, I can't
bear it; you and my dear mistress have done so much for me that I could never
repay it. But we shall never forget you, sir, and please God, we may someday see
mistress back again like herself; we must keep up hope, sir.”
Master gave johon his hand, but he did not speak, and they both left the
stable. The last sad day had come; the footman and the heavy luggage had gone
off the day before, and there was only master and mistress and her
maid. Ginger and I brought the carriage up to the hall door for the last time.
The servants brought out cushions and rugs and many other things; and when all
were arranged master came down the steps carrying them mistress in his
arms (I was on the side next to the house,
and could see all that went on); he placed her carefully in the carriage, while the
house servants stood around crying goodbye again,” he said; “we shall
not forget any of you,” and he got in.
“Drive on, John.” Joe jumped up, and we trotted slowly through the park and through the village,
where the people were standing on their doors to have a last look and to say, “God
bless them.” When we reached the railway station I think mistress walked from the carriage
to the waiting room I heard her say in her own sweet voice goodbye John. God bless
you.” I felt the rain twitch, but John made no answer; perhaps he could not
speak. As soon as Joe had taken the things out of the carriage John called
him to stand by the horses, while he went on the
platform. Poor Joe! he stood close up to our heads to hide his tears.
Very soon the train came puffing up into the station; then two or 3 minutes, and
the doors were slammed to, the guard whistled, and the train glided away,
leaving behind it only clouds of white smoke and some very heavy
hearts. When it was quite out of sight JN came back. “We shall never see her again,” he
said—“ —“never.” He took the RS mounted the box, and with Joe drove slowly home; but it was
not not our home
now end of chapter 21 end of part